## Rushabh Gosar

Graduate Student in Game Design & Development at IGM, Rochester Institute of Technology rushabh.techie@gmail.com

## Summary

Expertise: Windows Phone, Game Development(XNA), C#, JAVA and Unity.

Developed applications and games that are published on Windows Marketplace for Windows Phone 7,

Chairman ACM Student Chapter 2011- 2012,

Event Management Head of College's Technical Council,

Guinness World Record Holder for the attendee to an event with largest developers at one place at Microsoft Appathon Bangalore.

Microsoft Student Partner since Oct 2010.

## Experience

## CEO at http://rushabhgosar.com

March 2013 - Present (7 months)

Create the website, make a blog, make some free APIs for other developers. Now I am also writing my website again, to optimize it and adding my recent projects onto the website.

### Chief Technology Officer at Guid Softwares

February 2012 - December 2012 (11 months)

We at GUID Softwares develop software products for Mobile Phone and Tablet Machines. I specialize in innovation using the .NET Framework and have taken active part in development of our current product which is yet to be released on the Windows Phone and Windows 8 platforms. I have also designed the architecture of our Cloud Based services for the same product. I handle the product development with a few other colleagues that work design and assist in development.

2 recommendations available upon request

### Freelance Trainer at Edukinect

February 2011 - October 2012 (1 year 9 months)

As a Freelance Trainer at Edukinect I have taken workshops on Topics like Windows 8 and Windows Azure, .NET Framework and Windows Phone 7 at several colleges for a average duration of 6 days per college. Ensuring a great depth of knowledge imparted has also helped the students become developers and have their applications on the respective markets.

1 recommendation available upon request

#### Microsoft Student Partners at Microsoft

October 2010 - June 2012 (1 year 9 months)

Worked as a Windows Phone Developer. Learned advanced development on the platform. Developed and published two games as in intern on Windows Phone Marketplace

3 recommendations available upon request

### Intern at inoXapps

June 2011 - July 2011 (2 months)

I was the developer of two games, truth and dare and TapUps. Both of these games were built using XNA framework, and C#. These games were received popularly on Windows Phone store.

# Organizations

### **Association of Computing Machinery**

Chairman of College Student Chapter August 2011 to August 2012

## **Publications**

## **Cloud Gaming**

Imagine Cup IT Challenge April 12, 2012

Authors: Rushabh Gosar

This my paper presenting the concept of gaming on cloud, explaining the implementation, concept, history, features and challenges. This was a IT Challenge round 2 entry. This was one of a very innovative research concept that is the technology of the future because its advantages.

## Volunteer Experience

## YUVA MSP at YUVA Unstoppable

March 2011 - September 2011 (7 months)

Taken Digital Literacy workshops for underprivileged Students.

#### Shravak at JAIN DERASAR

August 2000 - Present (13 years 2 months)

Conducted donations camps

# Languages

#### **English**

(Full professional proficiency)

Hindi Gujarati Kutchi Marathi

(Full professional proficiency)
(Limited working proficiency)
(Native or bilingual proficiency)
(Limited working proficiency)

### **Test Scores**

#### **GRE**

October 2012 Score: 298

#### **TOEFL**

November 2012 Score:99/120

### Courses

### Bachelor's degree, Computer Science

University of Mumbai

ANALYSIS OF ALGORITHMS AND DESIGN

COMPUTER ORGANIZATION AND

ARCHITECTURE

DATA STRUCTURES AND FILES

DATABASE MANAGEMENT SYSTEMS

**COMPUTER GRAPHICS** 

**OPERATING SYSTEMS** 

COMPUTER NETWORK

ADVANCED DATABASE MANAGEMENT

**SYSTEMS** 

THEORY OF COMPUTATIONAL SCIENCE

ADVANCED COMPUTER NETWORKS

WEB ENGINEERING

SYSTEM PROGRAMMING AND COMPILER

**CONSTRUCTION** 

OBJECT ORIENTED SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

ADVANCED MICRO PROCESSORS

DATA WAREHOUSING AND MINING

DIGITAL SIGNAL AND IMAGE PROCESSING

ROBOTICS AND ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE

SYSTEM SECURITY

**SOFT COMPUTING** 

DISTRIBUTED COMPUTING

MULTIMEDIA SYSTEM DESIGN

SOFTWARE ARCHITECTURE

**HUMAN COMPUTING INTERACTION** 

DISCRETE STRUCTURE AND GRAPH THEORY

DIGITAL LOGIC DESIGN AND APPLICATION

### Certifications

#### **Microsoft Student Partner**

Microsoft October 2010 to August 2012

## **Projects**

#### Zoik it!

August 2012 to Present

Members: Rushabh Gosar, Nawaz Dhandala, Hatim

The application that allows you to connect to others of your own interest!

### **Immunity Buster**

January 2012 to Present

Members: Rushabh Gosar, Hatim Nagarwala, Shreyas Gune, Sushil Mohite

Immunity Buster is a 2D Game on Windows PC based on a social message of HIV/AIDS. The game is developed using XNA Game Studio 4.0. The game is a perfect mixture of learning and fun, as it allows user to take a control of the HIV virus and explore the body. Here the virus fights against the W.B.Cs of the body and makes his way into the body.

#### W-Cloud

March 2012 to Present

Members: Rushabh Gosar, Karthik Reddy, Chinmay Jain

This is a project based on Windows Azure that provides a communication medium to access your desktop files on your Windows Phone. This application uses WCF services, BLOBs, Queues, WPF, and Silverlight. The application consists of 3 modules, the cloud application, the windows phone client and the desktop background client. Additionally a website was also made for user registration, access control, management and providing extra features. Unfortunately the project couldn't go live because of the high costs associated with the project.

#### **Media Locker**

August 2012 to Present

Members:Rushabh Gosar, Hatim Nagarwala

This is a simple windows phone based application that uses isolated storage technique to store and password protect user images. The initial launch of this application consisted of Facebook upload, native editing of pictures, skydrive upload and adding back the image to the library. This application was later downgraded due to changed Facebook application policies and the launch of Windows Azure Mobile Services. This application is currently being rebuilt for windows phone 8 and will make use of the new Windows Phone 8 APIs.

#### Web APIs

May 2013 to Present

#### Members:Rushabh Gosar

This is a sub-domain of my original website, that provides open free APIs to developers for the usage of basic functionality such as saving high scores online for a game, and for converting text into images readily on the go. This website has currently a very small developer base, 6 developers presently.

## Skills & Expertise

**XNA** 

C++

**C**#

.NET

Java

**Windows Phone** 

Wordpress

**Photoshop** 

Joomla

**Windows Azure** 

WCF

**WPF** 

**Game Development** 

**Game Design** 

Silverlight

**Software Development** 

**Software Engineering** 

**Android** 

**Blackberry applications** 

**Engaging Speaker** 

**Dynamic Speaker** 

**ASP.NET** 

C

**JavaScript** 

**PHP** 

**HTML** 

Windows 7

**Kinect** 

**Software Documentation** 

Windows 8

WindowsRT

**Training** 

**Python** 

XAML

**WPF Development** 

**Microsoft Expression** 

**MySQL** 

**Visual Studio** 

**Cloud Computing** 

 $\mathbf{XML}$ 

## OOP HTML 5 Eclipse

## Education

#### **RIT**

Master of Science (MS), Game Design and Development, 2013 - 2015

Activities and Societies: IMG Society

### **University of Mumbai**

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science, 2008 - 2012

Grade: A

Activities and Societies: Member of IEEE

Member of ACM

## Wilson College, Chowpatty, Mumbai

High School, Science, 2006 - 2008

### Honors and Awards

Winner of the Best Idea at Windows 8 Hackathon, TechED 12 India,

Microsoft Student Partner,

Head For Event Management Team of Technical Council of College,

Developed a Website: http://rushabh.my3gb.com,

Made applications for Windows Phone 7

### **Interests**

Gaming, Computer Software Development and Testing, Windows Phone and Windows 8 Application Development.

# Rushabh Gosar

Graduate Student in Game Design & Development at IGM, Rochester Institute of Technology

rushabh.techie@gmail.com



# 6 people have recommended Rushabh

"Rushab is not just a coder but good software developer. I have seen him working at various instance. We have worked together in college for some projects, with that experiences I can assure you that he is a great team player. He is quite confident and very good at skills mentioned. Also we worked together closely and for almost 8 days together for college technical festival where he was event management head. So he even has good management skills. I recommend you Rushab to you."

— **Rajendra Patil**, *PHP Developer*, *Silgate IT Solutions Pvt. Ltd.*, worked directly with Rushabh at Guid Softwares

"Rushabh is one of the best programmers and one of the best technical geeks I know in this country. He always hunts for quality in whatever he does and I say this because, He'd never let the product ship until it meets the right quality standards. I'd love to recommend Rushabh to you."

— **Nawaz Dhandala**, *Founder and Managing Director*, *Guid Softwares*, managed Rushabh at Guid Softwares

"Rushabh Gosar is one of the Trainers at my company Edu-Kinect. As the CEO of the company, I have had frequent opportunities to interact with and observe him. I find him to be a promising engineer with good communication and presentation skills. Rushabh's selection was based on a technical interview. Besides his basic aptitude, I was impressed by his proficiency in Training & Mentoring, which he had developed on his own initiative. His fundamental concepts of C# and XNA Game Studio helped him to develop himself as a better mentor for his attendees. Rushabh has been a part of rigorous trainings at Paavai University at Salem, SR College at Warangal and VIT Vellore, Chennai Campus. He has evangelized on topics like .NET, Windows Phone 7, Windows 8, Windows Azure and basics of Game Development. I am impressed by his enthusiasm, keenness and his work rate. He has also ensured the completion of applications by many of his attendees and has also helped improve the quality of applications. Rushabh also represented my company as the chief guest at TechDays Pondicherry along with Govind Kanj the General Manager of Microsoft Training. Rushabh has an amazing hold over Windows 8 and is known for his in depth knowledge in that field. He has ability to communicate clearly, precisely and this has proved to be a great asset in the swift execution of his work. In his work, Rushabh has shown himself to be a very intelligent and hardworking trainer and a developer. He has been successful in the performance of all the work entrusted to him. His most striking quality is the commitment he shows in whatever he does. He is confident, down to earth, pleasant and well mannered and focused. Considering his motivation, perseverance and intelligence, I strongly believe that he will scale the highest peaks in his fields of interest. Thank You."

— **Mrityunjay Bhadauria**, *Research Engineer*, *Siemens Corporate Research*, worked directly with Rushabh at Edukinect

"Rushabh is a brilliant coder, an awesome trainer and a great human being. He is one of the best trainer i had ever met and he is a committed individual who likes to completes his job honestly, he inspires students accross the nation."

— Mohit Chhabra, Microsoft Student Partner, Microsoft, worked directly with Rushabh at Microsoft

"Rushabh is an excellent developer. he is a good learner and always share his knowledge with their peers."

— Ruchika Garg, Student, HMRITM, worked indirectly for Rushabh at Microsoft

"Rushabh is a great coder. I have seen his work . He is so good in his coding skills . He works on variety of platforms like Windows Phone, windows 8 , C , linux so on and so forth. Having worked with him as a Microsoft Student Parter, I have seen him excel in his life"

— **Apoorv Upadhyay**, *Microsoft Student Partners*, *Microsoft India Student*, worked directly with Rushabh at Microsoft

Contact Rushabh on LinkedIn